searchassociates.com 2019-08-29

# Search Associates Privacy Policy

This privacy policy explains how Search Associates collects, uses and protects any information provided to us when an individual or institution applies for or contracts to use any of its services.

Search Associates is committed to ensuring that the privacy of its users is protected. Search Associates has always conformed to the highest standards and best practices of data protection including the principles underlying the GDPR and other such laws. Users can be assured that any information gathered by Search Associates in the conduct of its business will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. 

## Sites covered by this Privacy Statement

This Policy applies to searchassociates.com, search-associates.net, search-associates.co.uk and all subsequent online sites launched in affiliation with or managed by Search Associates. Search Associates websites may contain links to third-party websites. Search Associates makes no claims or guarantees regarding the privacy policy of any site reachable through hyperlinks or redirects.  When visiting linked websites, visitors are encouraged to read each external sites’ privacy policy.

## Express Consent

By submitting an application or entering into a contract for our services, such an application or request for services by educator candidates and/or schools, will constitute express consent to our use of personal information in accordance with this privacy policy. 

## The purpose of our data collection

Search Associates is a leading recruitment firm in the world of international schools. For nearly thirty years it has placed teachers and administrators at the top international schools around the world. The only purpose to collect data from its clients, i.e. educational candidates and schools, is to establish suitability for membership with Search Associates and facilitate the recruitment of such educators by member schools. Both candidates and schools are carefully vetted by our global network of Senior Associates before any business relationship is established. In creating an account with Search Associates, an educational candidate or international school is establishing a business relationship with Search Associates based on a voluntary sharing of personal or institutional information, which is the context under which data is collected, processed and used. 

## What information do we collect

### Educational Candidates

The type of information we collect from educational candidates is information necessary to assess their suitability for employment by our member schools and membership with our organization. Search Associates does not control the policies of its member schools nor the policies of the countries in which those schools reside.  Search Associates promotes an anti-discrimination hiring process with all its member schools. Information collected includes:

  * Candidate personal information, e.g. name, date of birth, citizenship, current address and contact details. 
  * Educational qualifications and experience. 
  * Training and professional development experience. 
  * Relevant family details that have a bearing on employment positions under consideration. 
  * Employment preferences (including geography) 
  * Background information including criminal records and employment history. 
  * Communication between Search Associates, candidates and school recruiters. 
  * Essential medical history relevant in the context of employment in foreign countries, some with basic medical infrastructure. 
  * Information provided by referees, at the request of candidates, commenting on candidate's previous work experience. 
  * Job offers and eventual position placement information. 
  * Job fair registration details. 

### Member Schools and School Recruiters

The type of information we collect for schools is information required to transact our business operations of facilitating the employment of suitable educational candidates by these schools and includes:

  * Organizational information such as location, student enrollment, educational bodies certification, membership of associations and other such information.
  * Key personnel contact details. 
  * Communication between Search Associates and schools or Schools and candidates.
  * Pertinent information required for payment by schools to Search Associates for services rendered. 

### Referees

The type of information we collect from confidential referees is information necessary to assess an educational candidate’s suitability for employment by our member schools. Such information includes:

  * Contact details.
  * Relevant employment history and professional relationship to educational candidate.
  * Comments on an educational candidate’s previous work experience.

## What do we do with the information we gather

### Educational Candidates

Any personal information collected, held or used by Search Associates about educational candidates is predominantly used to assist them in finding the best fit employment with a member school. Ancillary uses include:

  * More finely understand a candidate’s needs and preferences.
  * Inform candidates about Search Associates’ current services and update them on new services.
  * Respond to a candidate or facilitate communication between a candidate and a school and/or school recruiter.
  * From time to time send a candidate newsletter and other similar communication on relevant topics (from which the candidate has the option of unsubscribing). 
  * To communicate and process agreed upon charges for Search Associates services.
  * Personalize some Search Associates web services.

### Member Schools and School Recruiters

Any personal information collected, held or used by Search Associates about member schools and school recruiters is used predominantly for the purpose of helping them find suitably qualified educational candidates. Ancillary uses include maintaining an updated record of financial transactions, to support the services that Search Associates delivers to schools.

## Disclosure

Search Associates will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others. It may however contact educational candidates and/or member schools about services it offers or enhancements to services. Search Associates may share personal information with trusted companies working on its behalf when it retains service providers to deliver new products/services. Such service providers are contractually required to keep information received from Search Associates confidential and may not use it for any purpose other than in delivery of said product and/or service. Except as described in the previous statement, Search Associates will not share personal information with any third parties without express permission, unless it is needed to: (i) respond to duly authorized information requests of governmental authorities; (ii) comply with any applicable law, regulation, subpoena, or court order.

## Data accuracy

Search Associates strives to keep your personal information accurately recorded. The implementation of technology, management processes and policies helps maintain data accuracy. We provide individuals with access to personal information that they provide and the ability to review and correct it. To protect the privacy and security of this information, steps are taken to verify individual identities, such as requiring a password and user ID, before granting access to data. To view and change the personal information that has been directly provided to Search Associates, individuals and schools can login via a unique email address and secure password to change/update any personal information.

## Modifying/withdrawing data 

Educational candidates who choose to use Search Associates give express permission to share all information contained in their profile with schools for the purpose of finding employment. At any time, if a candidate wishes to withdraw their information from display to schools they can do this directly from their candidate dashboard. Once a candidate deactivates their account, their information is immediately removed from display to all member schools.  If a member school wishes at any time to withdraw their school information from display to candidates, it can do so by contacting our School Coordinator.

Both schools and educational candidates may have the right to have your information completely removed from our database under the new GDPR guidelines and other laws. Educational candidates can initiate a request by contacting their assigned Associate and school can make a request directly to our School Coordinator.

## Data Security

Search Associates is committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures are in place to safeguard and secure the information collected from individuals and schools. 

All data in the Search Associates database is protected using standard database security controls such as authorized user accounts. Additionally, key sensitive data such as confidential questions responses are stored in encrypted form in the database. User passwords are hashed and salted into the database according to industry standards and using 128-bit encryption. 

Search Associates web servers, like our database server, sit behind a firewall.  However, in the case of the web servers, no public port is available. The web servers sit behind a load balancer that sends each user request to one of the balanced servers. By reducing the number of ports available, the attack surface of the site is significantly limited. Website code is also designed to prevent SQL injection attacks and is continually updated to ensure the code is not vulnerable and complies with the latest coding best practices.  Additionally, Search Associates websites require the use of Secure Sockets Layer (SSL or HTTPS) which encrypts data between client browsers and servers and keeps all data secure in transit from the browser to the server. 

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which may be downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Search Associates uses cookies and Google Analytics to identify service issues, provide custom content to users, and monitor site traffic. Search Associates also uses digital advertising and remarketing, including but not limited to use of Google, Facebook, and Instagram ads, which (may) include first and third-party cookie tracking. This may include collection of data including but not limited to email, first and last name, date of birth, gender, and location information, such as city, zip code, and country. 

More information about Google Analytics can be found here: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners>

## Incident response

In the unlikely event of a data or privacy breach, Search Associates will notify the affected users within 72 hours of becoming aware of such a breach. This is in compliance with the GDPR and industry standard business practice.

## Contacting us

Search Associates values your opinion. If you have comments or questions about this privacy statement, please send them via email to [admin@searchassociates.com](mailto:admin@searchassociates.com)
